

ANASTASIIA NOVIKOVA

- Carrer de la Torre dels Pardals, Barcelona, Spain 08032
- **11.04.2000**

+34655430564

- Warainian
- novikova.anastasiia2000@gmail.com

ABOUT ME

As a highly motivated Master's student in Biomedicine with three years of laboratory experience, I am eager to further my skills and advance my knowledge in the field of medical research. I am seeking a position that will provide me with the opportunity to expand my expertise and apply my knowledge to help improve people's health. With a passion for the field and a commitment to making a difference, I am confident that I will make a valuable contribution to the research team I join.

WORK HISTORY

LABORATORY TECHNICIAN, 08/2022 - Current

Josep Carreras Leukaemia Research Institute, Barcelona, Spain

- Immunological assays (flow cytometry; ELISA assays)
- Cell culture work (seeding and plating; FACS; transfection and transduction; gene editing CRISPR/Cas9; drug screening assay)
- Molecular biology techniques (DNA/RNA exraction; PCR; gel electrophoresis; next-generation sequencing (NGS))
- Bioinformatic tools (statistical analysis; sequence analysis; data visualization)

LABORATORY ASSISTANT, 10/2019 - 05/2022

Odesa Social Significance Disease Centre (OSDC), Odesa, Ukraine

- Participation in the international INNOVA4TB project HORIZON2020
- Basic molecular biology techniques (DNA/RNA extraction; real-time/qPCR)
- Maintain laboratory cleanliness and reagents (media/working solution preparation; sterilization; autoclaving)
- Bacteriological techniques (plating techniques; drug resistance tests; bacterial staining; microscopy)
- Immunological assays (flow cytometry; ELISA assays)

BACTERIOLOGIST'S ASSISTANT, 11/2016 - 01/2017

Odesa Regional Military Hospital, Odesa, Ukraine

- Bacterial culture maintanance (plating techniques)
- Antibiotic susceptibility/drug resistance tests
- Bacterial identification (Gram staining; microscopy)
- Maintain laboratory cleanliness and reagents (media preparation; sterilization; autoclaving)

EDUCATION

University of Barcelona, Barcelona, Spain, 09/2022 - Current

Master of Science in Biomedicine: Basic and Translational Research in Human Pathology

At present, I am pursuing my master's degree and concurrently working part-time as a laboratory technician in the Leukaemia and Immuno-Oncology group at the Josep Carreras Leukaemia Research Institute, where I am also engaged in my master's project. My research involves examining the impact of *PTPN11* gene mutations on the development of Acute Myeloid Leukaemia.

Odesa National I.I. Mechnikov University, Odesa, Ukraine, 09/2017 - 05/2021 Bachelor of Science in Biology

- Degree Thesis "Detecting molecular markers of resistance to Bedaquiline in the Mycobacteria Tuberculosis genome"
- Government academic scholarship 2017-2021, fully paid scholarship by Ministry of Education and Science Ukraine
- Average note original scale: 81,35/100 (GPA 3.1) EQF level 5
- The bachelor's program was aimed at obtaining 240 ECTS credits
- During my studies at university, I actively participated in various scientific events and extracurricular activities organized by the university: XVII/XVI Student Scientific Conference "English in Touch With Science" (2019/2018) with oral presentations; I actively participated in the events arranged by the student

council and university trade union, contributing my services as both a photographer and organizer

Participation in XIII International Summer School-Conference "Molecular Microbiology and Biotechnology" (2018); XIV International Summer-Conference School "Molecular Microbiology and Biotechnology" (2019); XV International Summer-Conference School "Molecular Microbiology and Biotechnology" (2020); XVI International Summer School-Conference "Molecular Biology, Biotechnology and Biomedicine" (2021)

INTERNSHIPS

07/2021 - 05/2022

Early-stage Researcher in Project "INNOVA4TB" at Institute Germans Trias i Pujol (IGTP), Barcelona

- Immunological assays (PBMCs isolation;Flow cytometry; ELISA assays)
- Molecular biology techniques (DNA/RNA exraction; PCR; Gel electrophoresis; next-generation sequencing (NGS))
- Cell viability assays (MTT; Trypan Blue staining)
- Cell culture work (seeding/plating; FACS; transfection and transduction; gene editing CRISPR/Cas9; drug screening assay)
- Participating in conferences and symposia, presenting interim results, and actively engaging with other project members through business trips to collaborate with external laboratories
- The INNOVA4TB project has received funding from the European Union's Horizon 2020 research and innovation programme under the Marie Skłodowska-Curie grant agreement No 823854

SKILLS

- Adaptability
- · Teamwork
- · Attention to details
- · Critical thinking

- · Continuous learning
- · Research and analytical skills
- Multitasking abilities
- Problem-solving

LIST OF PUBLICATIONS

- S.Gushcha, A.Novikova, et al. Assessment of the influence on natrium chloride water on the course of toxic liver damage in the experiment. Pharmacology OnLine Archives. 2021. Vol.3. 698-706.
- S.Gushcha, A.Novikova, et al. Autochthonous microbiota of mineral natural waters of Ukraine as a health maintenance factor. Abstracts of the I International Scientific and Technical Conference "Water Quality: Biomedical, Technological, Agricultural and Environmental Aspects". 2021. p58-59.
- S.Gushcha, A.Novikova, et al. Experimental studies of natural coniferous extract in different dilutions. Medical rehabilitation, balneology, physiotherapy. 2019. p35-40.
- V.Stepanova, A.Novikova, et al. Experience in the use of halo-aerosol therapy in the rehabilitation of patients with bronchial asthma. PainMedicine Journal. 2018. Vol.3. No.2/1. p40.
- S.Gushcha, A.Novikova, et al. Prospects for the use of underground mineral waters of the Eastern region of Ukraine in the rehabilitation of patients with osteoarthritis and dorsopathies. PainMedicine Journal. Vol.3. No. 2/1. p37.

LANGUAGES

Ukrainian Native

English	B2	Spanish	A2
Upper intermediate		Elementary	
German	B1	Russian	C2
Intermediate		Proficient	

REFEREES CONTACT INFORMATION

1) Dr. Laura Belver - Current Supervisor

Principal Investigator of the group in which I am doing my final Master's thesis.

Email: lbelver@carrerasresearch.org

Phone: (+34) 665832632

2) Dr. José Domínguez - Internship Supervisor

Principal Investigator of the group in which I did my Bachelor's research during my internship.

Email: jadominguez@igtp.cat Phone: (+34) 930330537

3) Prof. Kostiantyn Babov - Bachelor Thesis Supervisor

Director of The «Ukrainian Research Institute of Medical Rehabilitation and Resort Therapy of the Ministry of

Health of Ukraine»

Email: mrik.poliklinika@gmail.com

Phone: (+380) 487280653